<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-04T21:04:28+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Tim Feuring</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tommys &amp;amp; Jerrys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tommys-and-jerrys" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tommys &amp; Jerrys" /><published>2019-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crepes-et-galettes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tommys-and-jerrys">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What tastes better than a sweet crêpe or a hearty galette on a walk through the christmas market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I painted these signs by hand for a local food truck, so they can stand out with their handwritten signs – and delicious crepes and galettes, of course.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking" /><summary type="html">Process</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy to have you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy to have you" /><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I’m so happy to have you in my life!”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a thing we should tell our loved ones way more often. For that purpose, I created this little card with a custom lettering. When did you last tell someone that they are important to you? Call them right now and bring a smile on their face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: you’ll feel great afterwards, I promise :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Lettering" /><summary type="html">Process “I’m so happy to have you in my life!”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kohledampfer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kohledampfer" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal mining is history in Germany. A tradition looking back on hundreds of years of development is coming to an end. „Kohledampfer“ is a unique beer, brewed in small circulation for the graduation project of a brewers class in Dortmund, Germany. The historic background of the region regarding the omnipresent mining industry inspired the young brewers for creating a beer that pays tribute to the miners and their struggle and keeps their memory alive. For this purpose, they created a porter - black like the coal in a mine. Mining is closely connected to seafare historically - from this, the name and motive „Kohledampfer“ (roughly translates to steamboat) derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation project of the brewers, I developed a label as well as a logo mark and an illustration to represent the historic background and convey the mood of a typical hard-working miner. Black as coal in a mine, the beer appears - straightforward and direct, just like the miners of the past. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Illustration / Packaging" /><summary type="html">Process “Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christian &amp;amp; Vassil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christian &amp; Vassil" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, I developed a warm and happy visual style by combining typography and illustration to form a unique appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calligraphic letters used in the headline are derived from a custom font I designed. The tucan and the fox act as the wedding mascots and give all the visuals an especially cute touch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Wedding Invitation" /><summary type="html">Process Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sauerwein</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sauerwein" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sauerwein</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery approached its brand with a rather classic, maybe a bit old-fashioned look and feel. My aim was to refresh the visual appearance with a new logo and label while maintaining and communicating their core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauerwein is a real existing winery business. This project served the purpose of my personal exploration and does not reflect the actual brand of the Sauerwein family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">Process The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extra Butter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extra Butter" /><published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/extra-butter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra Butter is a custom, hand-designed logotype project of mine. 
From initial lettering as a pencil-sketch to refined vector artwork, it evolved to its final, playful look. It was later on used for screen-printing and now embellishes diverse clothes and fabrics from shirts to shopping bags.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation / Lettering" /><summary type="html">Process Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WC for Humans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WC for Humans" /><published>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate about unisex or genderless bathrooms in public spaces has been going on for years. No matter which point of view you might have on the topic or if it is relevant in your daily life, one thing is clear: the binary approach affects people and often makes the simple task of going to the toilet more complicated than necessary, whether the problem appears in the form of longer queues and waiting times for women at basically any social events, or the way non-binary-identifying people often feel mistreated and unaccepted through such a classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about time we pour less energy in fighting about different gender concepts, but focus on what truly unites us all – we are all human beings with dignity and deserve to be accepted from one another whereever we go. The simple task of making public toilets accessible for everyone is a small step into that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I am very happy that I could contribute a tiny bit to the cause by creating this sign-concept for a local restaurant. The letters were drawn by hand, lasercut from oak wood and then put up on the bathroom doors, where they now make a beautiful and warm impression to welcome anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking / Lettering" /><summary type="html">Process The debate about unisex or genderless bathrooms in public spaces has been going on for years. No matter which point of view you might have on the topic or if it is relevant in your daily life, one thing is clear: the binary approach affects people and often makes the simple task of going to the toilet more complicated than necessary, whether the problem appears in the form of longer queues and waiting times for women at basically any social events, or the way non-binary-identifying people often feel mistreated and unaccepted through such a classification.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dreamy Donuts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dreamy Donuts" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;It’s a sign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet donuts, delicious cakes, perfect coffee with latte-art on it and everything else you could wish for in a café. You just feel when a restaurant or cafe has that kind of soul to it, when everything is made with love and passion, when people put their hearts in and create beautiful sourroundings – to heartily welcome their customers to embrace the sweet things in life. And what underlines handmade, personal, delicious food made with love even more? Exactly, handmade signs made with the same personality and passion. For the grand opening of the cafe, I had the pleasure to design a concept and to hand-paint the signs for the store. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At the beginning of a (signpainting) project, there are always a bunch of open questions. What is the purpose of the sign? Is it a main information source or is it more decorational? Which information exactly should it transport, what are possible ways to produce and what fits best to the customer? What do the commodities allow?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this case, possibilities were pretty much open in any direction. The main goal was to create well-functioning signs that give customers a good orientation and fit to the brand and the style of the location. The overall look and feel should be high-quality, trustworthy, and transport love to the details. Looking for a way to convey these attributes, the idea of hand-painting the signs was close. Handpainted signs have personality. Each sign is unique, each letter individually written for an exact purpose and and exact place. It enrichens the overall look and feel of a location, and beyond plain information, it transports the craftsmenship and love for detail with it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With these questions in mind, the first job the be done before picking up a brush and paint was to sort out information and create a visual concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Starting with the basics: sorting information
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cafe, the menu was rather broad. There were loads of beverages and different kinds of food. In addition, the owner wanted to stay flexible to test out different dishes and see what works out best, especially regarding the donuts and bagels. To solve this problem and narrow it down for the signs, splitting the menu into two categories made sense: one fixed part for the beverages that do not change often, and another part that could be easily adjusted for the food. This way, the beverages would make out the major part of the handpainted signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Sketching out ideas for placement and form of the signs
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clustering the menu and deciding which information should go on the signs, the planning of size and position starts. The location of the café had high ceilings and a broad free space, which allowed for a wide sign of ~5 metres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Preparing the wooden boards with chalkboard paint
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the chalkboards are all custom tailored. The base is made of wooden board, then chalkboard paint is applied. You can ususally get all that is needed for preparing chalk boards from your local hardware store or order the materials online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Measuring and lining down the baselines for the sign. An improvised ruler (left) can help to easen the process
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to prepare for the letters! When transferring the sketches and positions to the board correctly, it is helpful to calculate the amount of rows and columns. Additionally, I like to make myself a kind of ruler with the correct measurements, this saves some time when drawing the baselines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Rough sketches to determine the size of the letters (left) and testing out the sizes on a draft paper before painting on the board (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all the baselines are ready to go and the board is marked. Previously I tested how the size of letters would work out optically. Also, I painted an example row with the final brushes on draft paper to determine the final look and style of letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    The critical phase: painting the menu on the board 
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything set and prepared, lets go! Row by row, I now paint the menu items on the board. At hand is the list to get everything in right order and a wet towel to erase baselines or errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Detail shot of the coffee menu
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding some final details – and it’s finished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    The boards hanging in their final place on the wall
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Final coffee and tea signs seperated
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This signpainting job was particularly fun and challenging. I’m very happy with the end result and I’m looking forward to more similar work.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking" /><summary type="html">It’s a sign</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Swipe Studio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swipe Studio" /><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;A mazing design studio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swipe is SinnerSchraders mobile studio, specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences – and it is the studio I had the luck to absolve my three year graphic design apprenticeship in. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Founded in 2010, it has expanded over time and is now located in the cities of Hamburg, Berlin and Zürich. On a regular basis, we organize activities for teambuilding or just hanging out and having a good time together. In 2019, the suggestion of printing and branding our own clothing by hand and came up. The idea for the screen printing workshop was born and with it, the challenge to design appealing graphics that people would want to wear. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Being especially interested in everything connected to typography and lettering, my wish was to create a bold and interesting logomark. While gathering inspiration from calligraphers, lettering artists and designers, I found grid-based, geometric type to have especially interesting bold aesthetics with rich contrasts. The idea was set, so let’s start the work! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It all starts with pen and paper. For me personally, sketching is the very best way to get thoughts out of your head, visualize ideas, to test concepts and to see what works and what does not. In my opinion, sketches do not need to be works of art or look especially great. For designing, they are more of a helpful tool for the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;first sketches on paper&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;I.) Letters filling former logo shape &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; II.) Combination of letters and outline of the logo shape&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first approach was to letter Swipe Studio to fit the geometric form of the former Swipe logo, which in the end did not end up working the way I imagined it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;I.) First draft with longer wording &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; II.) Roughly determining the letter shapes &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; III.) Refining positions of the letters &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, sketching the letters in the form of a grid seemed to be a much more promising approach. The interconnection and wrapping of the letters created an interesting aesthetic even in the quick sketches that needed to be explored further. After a few iterations the basic arrangement of the letters started to work out fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt; Process of refining the sketch and turning it into digital&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having set the basis, the next step was to arrange the letters in a geometric grid and to rebuild them as vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Finished logomark &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the logo only needed some more tweaks to get the contrast and whitespace just right. Fortunately, the constructed form of the letters and the way it was built using stroke vectors allows for quick adjustments of thickness. Et voilà, the logomark is finished!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Below, you can find some impressions from the screen printing workshop and the print results. We printed the logo on tote bags, shirts and even laptop cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Applying the color on the screen (left) and cleaning the screen after the printing process (right) &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Some of the printed fabrics – laptop cases, shirts and tote bags &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;The Swipe Studio logo painted on the studio wall in Hamburg &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initally, the logomark was designed and intended for having a fun screen printing workshop. But from this point, it started to live it’s own life. Over time, it was used more and more throughout the studio and eventually became the official Swipe logo that is now being used over several channels and painted over the walls in Hamburg, Berlin and Zurich.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Learn more about Swipe on 
&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/sinnerschrader-swipe-gmbh/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/swipestudio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">A mazing design studio</summary></entry></feed>