<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-14T11:38:43+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Tim Feuring</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tommys &amp;amp; Jerrys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tommys-and-jerrys" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tommys &amp; Jerrys" /><published>2019-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crepes-et-galettes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tommys-and-jerrys">&lt;p&gt;What tastes better than a sweet crêpe or a hearty galette on a walk through the christmas market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I painted these signs by hand for a local food truck, so they can stand out with their handwritten signs – and delicious crepes and galettes, of course.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking" /><summary type="html">What tastes better than a sweet crêpe or a hearty galette on a walk through the christmas market?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy to have you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy to have you" /><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/happy-to-have-you">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I’m so happy to have you in my life!”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a thing we should tell our loved ones way more often. For that purpose, I created this little card with a custom lettering. When did you last tell someone that they are important to you? Call them right now and bring a smile on their face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: you’ll feel great afterwards, I promise :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Lettering" /><summary type="html">“I’m so happy to have you in my life!”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kohledampfer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kohledampfer" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal mining is history in Germany. A tradition looking back on hundreds of years of development is coming to an end. „Kohledampfer“ is a unique beer, brewed in small circulation for the graduation project of a brewers class in Dortmund, Germany. The historic background of the region regarding the omnipresent mining industry inspired the young brewers for creating a beer that pays tribute to the miners and their struggle and keeps their memory alive. For this purpose, they created a porter - black like the coal in a mine. Mining is closely connected to seafare historically - from this, the name and motive „Kohledampfer“ (roughly translates to steamboat) derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation project of the brewers, I developed a label as well as a logo mark and an illustration to represent the historic background and convey the mood of a typical hard-working miner. Black as coal in a mine, the beer appears - straightforward and direct, just like the miners of the past. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Illustration / Packaging" /><summary type="html">“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christian &amp;amp; Vassil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christian &amp; Vassil" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil">&lt;p&gt;Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, I developed a warm and happy visual style by combining typography and illustration to form a unique appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calligraphic letters used in the headline are derived from a custom font I designed. The tucan and the fox act as the wedding mascots and give all the visuals an especially cute touch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Wedding Invitation" /><summary type="html">Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sauerwein</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sauerwein" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sauerwein</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein">&lt;p&gt;The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery approached its brand with a rather classic, maybe a bit old-fashioned look and feel. My aim was to refresh the visual appearance with a new logo and label while maintaining and communicating their core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauerwein is a real existing winery business. This project served the purpose of my personal exploration and does not reflect the actual brand of the Sauerwein family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extra Butter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extra Butter" /><published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/extra-butter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter">&lt;p&gt;Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra Butter is a custom, hand-designed logotype project of mine. 
From initial lettering as a pencil-sketch to refined vector artwork, it evolved to its final, playful look. It was later on used for screen-printing and now embellishes diverse clothes and fabrics from shirts to shopping bags.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation / Lettering" /><summary type="html">Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WC for Humans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WC for Humans" /><published>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans">&lt;p&gt;The debate about unisex or genderless bathrooms in public spaces has been going on for years. No matter which point of view you might have on the topic or if it is relevant in your daily life, one thing is clear: the binary approach affects people and often makes the simple task of going to the toilet more complicated than necessary, whether the problem appears in the form of longer queues and waiting times for women at basically any social events, or the way non-binary-identifying people often feel mistreated and unaccepted through such a classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about time we pour less energy in fighting about different gender concepts, but focus on what truly unites us all – we are all human beings with dignity and deserve to be accepted from one another whereever we go. The simple task of making public toilets accessible for everyone is a small step into that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I am very happy that I could contribute a tiny bit to the cause by creating this sign-concept for a local restaurant. The letters were drawn by hand, lasercut from oak wood and then put up on the bathroom doors, where they now make a beautiful and warm impression to welcome anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking / Lettering" /><summary type="html">The debate about unisex or genderless bathrooms in public spaces has been going on for years. No matter which point of view you might have on the topic or if it is relevant in your daily life, one thing is clear: the binary approach affects people and often makes the simple task of going to the toilet more complicated than necessary, whether the problem appears in the form of longer queues and waiting times for women at basically any social events, or the way non-binary-identifying people often feel mistreated and unaccepted through such a classification.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Swipe Studio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swipe Studio" /><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio">&lt;p&gt;SinnerSchrader Swipe is a Studio specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences. We are a small Team of approximately 30 people in Hamburg and regularly gather together in certain teamevents. This year, we decided to screen print our own custom clothing. For this case, the goal was to create a new custom logomark to represent our studio in a casual way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exploring different directions, it became clear that it had to be a typography-inspired approach with a rather bold look. I started sketching out several ideas on paper, and in the end came up with an arrangement of letters and shapes that end up fitting together in a perfect square. I transferred the analog design to digital and refined it furthermore. We ended up screen printing laptop-bags, shirts and hoodies in a variety of sizes and colors - some of which can be seen below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">SinnerSchrader Swipe is a Studio specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences. We are a small Team of approximately 30 people in Hamburg and regularly gather together in certain teamevents. This year, we decided to screen print our own custom clothing. For this case, the goal was to create a new custom logomark to represent our studio in a casual way.</summary></entry></feed>