<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-21T17:08:11+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Tim Feuring</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Shorebird</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shorebird" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shorebird" /><published>2019-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shorebird</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shorebird">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by wandering around the mud flats and watching birds on a vacation by the north sea, I drew this illustration of a shorebird. It is made by pen and ink and was directly scanned from my sketchbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of my free time with different art and design topics, including drawing and illustrating. I especially enjoy the vintage look and feel classic pen and ink illustrations evoke, as they distill to the necessary visual elements and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Illustration" /><summary type="html">Inspired by wandering around the mud flats and watching birds on a vacation by the north sea, I drew this illustration of a shorebird. It is made by pen and ink and was directly scanned from my sketchbook.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kohledampfer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kohledampfer" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal mining is history in Germany. A tradition looking back on hundreds of years of development is coming to an end. „Kohledampfer“ is a unique beer, brewed in small circulation for the graduation project of a brewers class in Dortmund, Germany. The historic background of the region regarding the omnipresent mining industry inspired the young brewers for creating a beer that pays tribute to the miners and their struggle and keeps their memory alive. For this purpose, they created a porter - black like the coal in a mine. Mining is closely connected to seafare historically - from this, the name and motive „Kohledampfer“ (roughly translates to steamboat) derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation project of the brewers, I developed a label as well as a logo mark and an illustration to represent the historic background and convey the mood of a typical hard-working miner. Black as coal in a mine, the beer appears - straightforward and direct, just like the miners of the past. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Illustration, Packaging" /><summary type="html">“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Iconset</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/iconset" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Iconset" /><published>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/iconset</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/iconset">&lt;p&gt;Living in urban spaces brings various aspects of life together - means of mobility, lifestyle, nature or everyday life locations like universities, gastronomy or stores, just to name a few. For this occasion, I created an icon family which brings these aspects together in a harmonious and appealing visual style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project served the purpose of exploring techniques of iconography and was designed for use on mobile devices. These icons could for example be used in a lifestyle-app or on a map.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Iconography" /><summary type="html">Living in urban spaces brings various aspects of life together - means of mobility, lifestyle, nature or everyday life locations like universities, gastronomy or stores, just to name a few. For this occasion, I created an icon family which brings these aspects together in a harmonious and appealing visual style.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fraktur</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fraktur" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fraktur" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fraktur</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fraktur">&lt;p&gt;The calligraphy „Fraktur“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a broad-edged pen. Here you can see a gothic calligraphy, also called fraktur. The name „fraktur“ derives from its letterforms, which are edged, giving the letter a broken or fractured look. This font style was widely spread among writers and in book printing in Europe. Gothic fonts were common reading fonts in books or newspapers up until the 20th century. Today, they are usually not used in reading contexts anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art of calligraphy, handlettering and typography in general are one of my favorite subjects in design. Whether it is in my daily work as a designer or my free time - composition, the practical execution and details of letters as well as readability and the conveying of meaning and emotions (the list could go on) are things I enjoy dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Calligraphy" /><summary type="html">The calligraphy „Fraktur“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a broad-edged pen. Here you can see a gothic calligraphy, also called fraktur. The name „fraktur“ derives from its letterforms, which are edged, giving the letter a broken or fractured look. This font style was widely spread among writers and in book printing in Europe. Gothic fonts were common reading fonts in books or newspapers up until the 20th century. Today, they are usually not used in reading contexts anymore.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minimum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minimum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minimum" /><published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minimum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minimum">&lt;p&gt;The calligraphy „minimum“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a classic broad-edged pen and afterwards digitalized. Here you can see a classic italic calligraphy, a style which was widely spread among writers before the industrial book printing process conquered first europe and then the rest of the world. Early Antiqua printing fonts evolved from this style. The word minimum is a good practice for getting a feeling for the spacing of letters, which plays an essential role in typography. Even spaced letters lead to a harmonious, satisfying look and feel and improve redability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art of calligraphy, handlettering and typography in general are one of my favorite subjects in design. Whether it is in my daily work as a designer or my free time - composition, the practical execution and details of letters as well as readability and the conveying of meaning and emotions (the list could go on) are things I enjoy dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Calligraphy" /><summary type="html">The calligraphy „minimum“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a classic broad-edged pen and afterwards digitalized. Here you can see a classic italic calligraphy, a style which was widely spread among writers before the industrial book printing process conquered first europe and then the rest of the world. Early Antiqua printing fonts evolved from this style. The word minimum is a good practice for getting a feeling for the spacing of letters, which plays an essential role in typography. Even spaced letters lead to a harmonious, satisfying look and feel and improve redability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Xenon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/xenon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xenon" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/xenon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/xenon">&lt;p&gt;The calligraphy „Xenon“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a classic broad-edged pen and afterwards digitalized. Here you can see a classic italic calligraphy, a style which was widely spread among writers before the industrial book printing process conquered first europe and then the rest of the world. Early Antiqua printing fonts evolved from this style. Looking at the angled strokes on the „O“ or the „e“ and the differing stroke-widths in each letter, you can clearly recognize their origin - handmade letters, for which broad-edged pens were used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art of calligraphy, handlettering and typography in general are one of my favorite subjects in design. Whether it is in my daily work as a designer or my free time - composition, the practical execution and details of letters as well as readability and the conveying of meaning and emotions (the list could go on) are things I enjoy dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Calligraphy" /><summary type="html">The calligraphy „Xenon“ evolved as a free project and mainly served the purpose of exploring and training my typographic abilities. It was made by hand with a classic broad-edged pen and afterwards digitalized. Here you can see a classic italic calligraphy, a style which was widely spread among writers before the industrial book printing process conquered first europe and then the rest of the world. Early Antiqua printing fonts evolved from this style. Looking at the angled strokes on the „O“ or the „e“ and the differing stroke-widths in each letter, you can clearly recognize their origin - handmade letters, for which broad-edged pens were used.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extra Butter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extra Butter" /><published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/extra-butter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter">&lt;p&gt;Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra Butter is a custom, hand-designed logotype project of mine. 
From initial lettering as a pencil-sketch to refined vector artwork, it evolved to its final, playful look. It was later on used for screen-printing and now embellishes diverse clothes and fabrics from shirts to shopping bags.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation / Lettering" /><summary type="html">Adding a little bit of Extra Butter on top.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gemeinschaftsgarten Vechta</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gemeinschaftsgarten-vechta" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gemeinschaftsgarten Vechta" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gemeinschaftsgarten-vechta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gemeinschaftsgarten-vechta">&lt;p&gt;Gardening is a popular and fun hobby. It is calming, connects us closer with nature and teaches us to value the resources we are given, as we learn to grow and take care of different plants from beautiful flowers to even growing our own vegetables - and it is even more valuable when we share our knowledge and experiences with our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring these values closer into our focus and to have fun exploring the wide possibilities of gardening in an engaging and open environment, is the goal of the community garden project in Vechta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created an exciting logo solution using a combination of iconography and typography to communicate the playful, open-minded and positive character of the community gardening project in Vechta and the people behind it. What are you still waiting for? Come and bring your garding gloves with you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">Gardening is a popular and fun hobby. It is calming, connects us closer with nature and teaches us to value the resources we are given, as we learn to grow and take care of different plants from beautiful flowers to even growing our own vegetables - and it is even more valuable when we share our knowledge and experiences with our community.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sauerwein</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sauerwein" /><published>2019-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sauerwein</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein">&lt;p&gt;The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery approached its brand with a rather classic, maybe a bit old-fashioned look and feel. My aim was to refresh the visual appearance with a new logo and label while maintaining and communicating their core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauerwein is a real existing winery business. This project served the purpose of my personal exploration and does not reflect the actual brand of the Sauerwein family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Swipe Studio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swipe Studio" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio">&lt;p&gt;SinnerSchrader Swipe is a Studio specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences. We are a small Team of approximately 30 people in Hamburg and regularly gather together in certain teamevents. This year, we decided to screen print our own custom clothing. For this case, the goal was to create a new custom logomark to represent our studio in a casual way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exploring different directions, it became clear that it had to be a typography-inspired approach with a rather bold look. I started sketching out several ideas on paper, and in the end came up with an arrangement of letters and shapes that end up fitting together in a perfect square. I transferred the analog design to digital and refined it furthermore. We ended up screen printing laptop-bags, shirts and hoodies in a variety of sizes and colors - some of which can be seen below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">SinnerSchrader Swipe is a Studio specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences. We are a small Team of approximately 30 people in Hamburg and regularly gather together in certain teamevents. This year, we decided to screen print our own custom clothing. For this case, the goal was to create a new custom logomark to represent our studio in a casual way.</summary></entry></feed>