<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-06T15:02:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Tim Feuring</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kohledampfer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kohledampfer" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/kohledampfer">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal mining is history in Germany. A tradition looking back on hundreds of years of development is coming to an end. „Kohledampfer“ is a unique beer, brewed in small circulation for the graduation project of a brewers class in Dortmund, Germany. The historic background of the region regarding the omnipresent mining industry inspired the young brewers for creating a beer that pays tribute to the miners and their struggle and keeps their memory alive. For this purpose, they created a porter - black like the coal in a mine. Mining is closely connected to seafare historically - from this, the name and motive „Kohledampfer“ (roughly translates to steamboat) derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation project of the brewers, I developed a label as well as a logo mark and an illustration to represent the historic background and convey the mood of a typical hard-working miner. Black as coal in a mine, the beer appears - straightforward and direct, just like the miners of the past. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Illustration / Packaging" /><summary type="html">Process “Vor der Hacke ist es Duster.” (under the pickaxe, it is dark)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christian &amp;amp; Vassil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christian &amp; Vassil" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/christian-und-vassil">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, I developed a warm and happy visual style by combining typography and illustration to form a unique appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calligraphic letters used in the headline are derived from a custom font I designed. The tucan and the fox act as the wedding mascots and give all the visuals an especially cute touch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Wedding Invitation" /><summary type="html">Process Marrying the person you love is amongst the most beautiful experiences one can possibly have. For your special day, everything should feel perfect – and that includes the way you announce your wedding to your friends and family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sauerwein</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sauerwein" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sauerwein</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sauerwein">&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery approached its brand with a rather classic, maybe a bit old-fashioned look and feel. My aim was to refresh the visual appearance with a new logo and label while maintaining and communicating their core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauerwein is a real existing winery business. This project served the purpose of my personal exploration and does not reflect the actual brand of the Sauerwein family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">Process The Sauerweins are a family of winemakers, owning a small winery business near to the Mosel in western Germany. Their roots go back to the 17th century and originally derive from southern Tyrol. Since 1924, they produce fine wines that are renowned well beyond their closer region.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zersetzer, Symbionten, Verwerter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/zersetzer-series" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zersetzer, Symbionten, Verwerter" /><published>2019-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/zersetzer-series</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/zersetzer-series">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt; Reviving an old printing technique – Swedish style &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumbling heavy stones around. Grinding and rasping them for hours with sands and stone work tools. Rinsing them with water every few minutes and drying them with manual fans. Repeating that same process for hours. Applying thick oily pastes and gum to the stone. Speckling them with chemicals, acid and lamp oil repeatedly. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sounds like hard work? It is! But why do all of this anyway? We are doing it to learn a printing technique that has been an industry-wide standard for centuries - the technique of lithography. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lithography (roughly translates to “stone printing”) is a flat printing technique. This means that you print an image with a flat surface. In this case, with a flat stone. It’s a chemical printing process: the basic principle behind it is that oil repels water. Most likely, you once tried mixing both - doesn’t work so well. In Lithography, only certain areas of the stone that were specifically prepared take up the oily ink. Metaphorically spoken, the stone has a “memory” of where the ink touched it.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the following, I’ll take you with me on the process of printing a lithography from sketch to finished print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;index-list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 
        &lt;a href=&quot;#step01&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; Step 01 – Planning the series &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;#step02&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; Step 02 – Preparing the stones &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         &lt;a href=&quot;#step03&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; Step 03 – Bringing the motif to the stone &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         &lt;a href=&quot;#step04&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; Step 04 – Preparing the stone for printing &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;    
    &lt;li&gt;
         &lt;a href=&quot;#step05&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; Step 05 – Printing &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;#step06&quot; class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt; The final edition &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    Step 01 – Planning the series 
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step01&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some like it more to paint into the blue – being a bit more of a planner, I took a bit of time to work out a concept for my series. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The series focuses around the interconnection of humans and nature. We are part of nature, part of the natural cycles and the ecosystem, no matter how far we try to separate us from it. All different kinds of organisms live in strong interconnection and interdependence – plants, animals, fungi, even the smallest microbes, they all play an important role in our ecosystem. In each of the three motifs of the series, I pick out one group of organisms and set it in relation with human hands to underline our dependency with nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    Step 02 – Preparing the stones
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step02&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a lithography from scratch takes a lot of time and physical effort. The first step, before you can transfer a motif onto a stone, is to plan the size of the print and to find matching stones. The stones for lithography come in different forms and sizes, from postcard-size to huge plates that one person can not carry alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Choosing stones for printing (left) and grinding them (right). The motif on the stone will be erased forever (artist of the previous motif unknown)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When having found two matching stones, the physical work starts. You carry the stones to a workbench and start to grind off the layers of the previous motif by moving one stone over another in a circular motion. A stone will usually be used for printing as long as possible, until it is literally gone. With each new motif, a small layer of the stone gets erased. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is one reasons lithographs are so precious – a motif can only be printed for a certain period of time. When the printing process ends, the stone finds it way back into the shelf and the motif gets erased to make room for a new one. It can then never be reprinted again – lithographs are usually a very limited edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Grinding Sand and water combine with fragments of the stone to a cement-like paste
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While grinding, the mixture of sand, water and more and more stone fragments will combine into a thick paste-like substance. The more and more stone fragments come off the stone, the thicker the substance gets and the harder it will be to move the stone. For that reason, you will wash off the paste with water and apply new grinding sand several times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        A half-erased motif on the stone (left) and the final, clean stone (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process, you have to check on the stone several times to see how you are proceeding. In the example above, you can see a partly grinded stone. The motif is erased near the borders, but still visible in the middle. After some more effort, in the end, you get a smooth stone with a clean surface that is ready to be drawn on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    Step 03 – Bringing the motif to the stone
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step03&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything smooth and clean? Excellent. Now it’s time to get the art on the stone. 
The most crucial part of the long process is, of course, bringing your motif onto the stone without messing it up. I started with drawing small thumbnail sketches until the composition felt just right for me. Then I worked out the detailed sketch, matching to the actual size and proportion of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        From first thumbnail sketches (left) to the final sketch for transferring (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, the thumbnail sketch is already close to the final version. This doesn’t have to be the case, and things can still be changed and explored in the process. For example, I first planned the letters to be in the bottom corner and changed the position again afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Working out the typography – every letter is drawn by hand
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the series, the letters are equally important as drawing the rest of the motif. Each letter is individually drawn. Here, you can see the final sketch of the letters that is transferred onto the stone.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now to the tricky part – we directly print on the paper with our stone. Therefore, the whole motif has to be mirrored, assuming we don’t want to read the wrong way around. A trick to make this easier is a light table. With its help, we can rearrange the whole composition and turn the letters around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Mirroring the whole motif with the help of a lighting table
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above, you can see how I arranged my composition and mirrored it. Each individual piece of the motif can be cut out and moved around. Then, I traced the final (mirrored) composition onto a fresh piece of paper. In the next step, I transfer this master sketch using a special foil with pigments on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        The mirrored sketch is transferred onto the stone with a special pigment foil
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is easy: you retrace every line of the sketch, and the pigment gets transferred onto the stone. If you ever got a tattoo, the process will feel familiar to you. This will help us to get very precise results and makes the exact transfer of fine lines, like for the typography, possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Transfer to stone in progress (left) to finished version (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line by line gets transferred to the stone, until you have a finished blueprint in the end. Now, I paint the actual ink onto the stone. Now, nothing is allowed to go wrong, as errors can not easily be erased. In my series, I work with two different sorts of color: opaque ink and lithographic chalk. The ink will be pitch black, while the chalk allows for fine details and gradients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Painting the background pitch black with ink, while creating fine details in the hand with chalk
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it – the motif is completed on the stone. Painting the letters with a very fine brush was the most intense part. Now we can continue with the final step before printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    Step 04 – Preparing the stone for printing
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step04&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to reproduce the artwork, the stone now has to be prepared with several chemical powders and tinctures. Different lithographers have slightly varying approaches to this process, but they all serve the same purpose – making the stone open to take up the ink where it should be, and repel the ink where it should not. In the process, chemicals get applied in a specific order: colophony and tackum powder, acid, gum arabic, lamp oil, and more. The process will not be explained in detail here, it should just give an impression on how the stone is worked with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Applying colophonium powder (left) and etching the motif with acid (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All steps in the preparation process serve the purpose of giving the stone the ideal characteristics for printing. At the end, the ink the stone was drawn on with gets erased with lamp oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Rubbing out the ink with lamp oil at the end of the preparation process
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the stone is “empty”. The ink is washed out, but you can see a big difference in the areas of the stone. The parts that have not been drawn on before seem smooth and almost elevated. The areas that had ink on them seem to be muted (they don’t reflect the light) and have a texture instead. Now, the printing Ink can be applied with a roller. It is crucial to keep the stone wet in the whole printing process. If the stone gets dry and you ink it, you might ruin your motif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        The stone before inking (left) and with ink applied (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    Step 05 – Printing
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step05&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are ready to print! Now all our efforts pay off and become a printed lithography series. The first step in the process is to apply the printing ink onto the stone. This is done with an ink roller. Before applying, the stone is made wet with a sponge. Usually, you repeat this step until you have applied enough ink. As my motif should be pitch black and saturated, I rolled on ink about four times for each print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
     &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-13.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Video: Inking the stone with an ink roller
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After inking the stone, the paper is placed on it. This too must be done carefully, as the position can not be adjusted anymore when the paper has touched the ink. To position it evenly, a frame can come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Positioning the paper on the stone. A frame (L shape on the right) can come in handy
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we need pressure to transfer the ink onto the paper. For that, we place a clean plexiglass pane on it. Then, the squeegee is positioned and pressure is applied with the lever. The gears get turned and move the tabletop through the press together with the paper. This evenly applies pressure to the whole paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Clamping the paper and stone into the press and applying pressure
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we need pressure to transfer the ink onto the paper. For that, we place a clean plexiglass pane on it. Then, the squeegee is positioned and pressure is applied with the lever. The gears get turned and move the tabletop through the press together with the paper. This evenly applies pressure to the whole paper. The printing is done – now we only need to take the paper off the stone and dry them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-16.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Video: Taking the print off the stone after the printing process
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, the prints will be air-dried for a few days. The oil-based ink takes longer to dry than regular, water-based inks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-17.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Finished prints drying in the workshop
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the printing sessions, the walls of the workshops are hanging full of prints. The smell of ink and machine grease fills the air. All in all, the workshops of Tidaholm are a very special surrounding to work in and feel like time travel back into the old days, where lithography was a printing standard.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, the only thing left is the finishing touch: numbering and signing the editions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;anchor-container&quot;&gt;
    The final edition
    &lt;div class=&quot;scroll-anchor&quot; id=&quot;step06&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working in the Swedish workshops, I’ve printed a series of three motifs. The edition is limited to 15 prints each, every print numbered and signed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; I. Die Zersetzer &lt;i style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;(engl. decomposers)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fungi are the garbage disposal of nature, decomposing dead organisms and recycling organic matter into fertile soil. The first artwork showcases the important role of fungi in our ecosystem.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; II. Die Symbionten &lt;i style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;(engl. symbionts)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living together in harmony and benefitting from each other – that’s one of the more beautiful sides of nature. In my second artwork, I want to lay emphasis on this peaceful aspect by combining the rising human hand with uplifting flora. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; III. Die Verwerter &lt;i style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;(engl. utilizers)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiders, bugs, caterpillars, snails – often unfairly underestimated and overlooked because they look strange and disgust us. But they as well play a vital role for our lives – and be it by snatching mosquitos out of the air for us so we can enjoy our summer nights in peace.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the great workshops, I was lucky to get my series featured in a Swedish newspaper article together with some of my fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/zersetzer/zersetzer-article-21.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
        Swedish newspaper featuring the printing series
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this journey into the world of lithography and my printing series. I created this work as a part of the seminar “Der Rote Faden” under the guidance of Prof. Ellen Sturm in Tidaholm Sweden, summer 2022.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Lithography" /><summary type="html">Reviving an old printing technique – Swedish style</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Screen Memories</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/screen-memories" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Screen Memories" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/screen-memories</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/screen-memories">&lt;div class=&quot;screen-memories-container&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;A component-based variable font experiment&lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
        At the base of most design systems, there is a grid. A grid can help to organize a design, structure it’s contents and give guidance by establishing a visual hirarchy – but it can also be a restriction. Especially in the early days of digitalization, low screen resolutions created clear technical boundaries on how graphics could be displayed. At the very latest with the distribution of the first personal computers using visual interfaces, a formerly niche area in design became more and more important: digital interface design. Due to rather low resolutions in early displays, designers then had to deal with the challenge of transferring formerly unrestricted design rules and patterns into very tight corset of units, the pixels, in the best way possible. 
        &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        This led to a whole new aesthetic of shapes, especially for fonts – curves and other letterform details needed to be pressed in a tight, rectangular pixel grid. Thanks to the technical development of display resolutions in the last decades, designers now have more possibilities than ever to produce fine-detailed forms and display them in every way possible. But the aesthetics of pixelated fonts are still in our minds today and remind us of the early days of digital applications.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    

    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Lowercase letter N in high resolution with fine details (left) and approximations using different grids (font: Open Sans)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Designing graphics under tight restrictions like these is also interesting in the way that it forces us to &lt;i&gt;reduce forms to their necessary essence,&lt;/i&gt; so that we can still recognise them. So in a way, early digital fonts were also unavoidably minimalistic. 
        &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        Another development in the technology of digital fonts in the last years is the concept of variable fonts. Variable means that forms can be gradually  transformed from one variant to another –  and every possible step in between can be displayed as well. 
        With this feature, variable fonts open up a great range of possibilities in design.
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Principle of variable fonts: the complete range between two designed states of a form (A and B) can be computed&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h4&gt;The idea: combining the old and the new&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        While studying the possibilities of variable fonts and the history of early digital fonts, the idea of combining aspects of both of them formed: the flexibility of variable fonts in interplay with the restrictions of early pixel fonts.
        This article illustrates the outcome of my experiments about creating a digital font that combines a restricted grid together with flexible, variable units (components).
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    Before going into the experiments, let me shortly introduce the thoughts behind the construction of the letters. The letters are constructed in a grid of rows. The basic style is a regular sans serif. A special feature of the font is the extreme high x-height, the low space for ascenders and the completely missing space for descenders (meaning the descenders are fit inside of the x-height space. This underlines the restriction of fitting letters in a very small space and at the same times allows for the font to be used with a very narrow line height.
    &lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-02.5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Weight variations of the letter A. You can see how the components align to the grid&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;The extreme x-height and the absence of ascenders allows the font to be set with very low line-heights&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h4&gt;Introducing variable components&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        There are four axes in this variable font that can each be manipulated seperately. Every axis affects the base component of the letters differently, as demonstrated below: 
    &lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&quot;interactive-container-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;article-interactive-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;component-explanation&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;component-example&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;component-example-glyph&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base wght-loop&quot;&gt;°&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;component-example-subline&quot;&gt; Weight &lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;component-example&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;component-example-glyph&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base form-loop&quot;&gt;°&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;component-example-subline&quot;&gt; Form &lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;component-example&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;component-example-glyph&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base slnt-loop&quot;&gt;°&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;component-example-subline&quot;&gt; Slant &lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;component-example&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;component-example-glyph&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base angl-loop&quot;&gt;°&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;component-example-subline&quot;&gt; Angle &lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot; interactive-container-subline&quot;&gt;The four variable axes in the base component: &lt;i&gt;Thickness, Form, Slant and Angle&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;The adjustment of the basic component in different axes allows for the letters to change its properties and appearance completely. We can not only change one axis and one property at a time, but iterate between different axes and let the application calculate all possible versions in between, which leads to some interesting results. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

    &lt;h4&gt;Letterform construction&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The letterforms themselves are entirely constructed of the base components shown above. A change in the base components leads to a change of the whole letter. Aditionally to the change in the base component itself, the arrangement that makes up the letter can be adjusted, in this case for creating an italic version with the Slant Axis.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hover over the letters to see how each axis affects the look of the letter.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;axis-explanation&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;axis-box&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5&gt;Weight&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base axis-example wght&quot;&gt;^ A&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        
        &lt;div class=&quot;axis-box&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5&gt;Form&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base axis-example form&quot;&gt;^ A&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;axis-box&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5&gt;Slant&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base axis-example slnt&quot;&gt;^ A&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;axis-box&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5&gt;Component Angle&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;screenmemories-base axis-example angl&quot;&gt;^ A&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- 
    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Weight&lt;/h4&gt;    
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base weight-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;Weight&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Form&lt;/h4&gt;    
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base form-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;Form&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Slant&lt;/h4&gt;    
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base slant-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;Slant&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Component Angle&lt;/h4&gt;    
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base angle-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;Angle&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;All variable axes together&lt;/h4&gt;    
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base all-axes-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;All axes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;

    &lt;h4&gt;Character Set&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The font includes all uppercase and lowercase letters, the numbers and basic interpunctuation.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Upper- and lowercase alphabet&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Numbers and basic punctuation&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;h4&gt;Manipulating the axes&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The basic principle is clear – a manipulation of the base component changes the apperance of the letter. Now, we can change the properties of the font and mix between the axes to our liking. 
        &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        Use the editor below to adjust the axes of the font. You can also enter your own text!
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;!-- PLACEHOLDER FOR FUNTIONAL MODAL
    &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;


    &lt;!-- PLACEHOLDER FOR FUNTIONAL MODAL --&gt;


      &lt;!-- SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST 
        SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST
        SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST --&gt;

    &lt;!-- &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-article-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;main class=&quot;interactive-slider-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;h1 class=&quot;demo-text&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable=&quot;&quot;&gt; Hello &lt;/h1&gt;
                &lt;!-- &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage-axes&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;h1 id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;stage-text demo-text screenmemories-base all-axes-example&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable&gt;&amp;nbsp;All axes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h1&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
    
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;controls&quot;&gt;
                &lt;!-- Weight Controls --&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;slider-container&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;slider-controls&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;label for=&quot;text-weight&quot; class=&quot;slider-label&quot;&gt;
                            Weight: &lt;span class=&quot;output&quot; data-index=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   
                        &lt;/label&gt;
                        &lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;800&quot; value=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;slider&quot; id=&quot;text-weight&quot; name=&quot;text-weight&quot; data-index=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;
                        &lt;a class=&quot;slider-button underline&quot; data-index=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
                            Reset
                        &lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;!-- Width Controls --&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;slider-container&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;slider-controls&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;label for=&quot;text-width&quot; class=&quot;slider-label&quot;&gt;
                            Form: &lt;span class=&quot;output&quot; data-index=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  
                        &lt;/label&gt;
                        &lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;800&quot; value=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;slider&quot; id=&quot;text-width&quot; name=&quot;text-width&quot; data-index=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
                        &lt;a class=&quot;slider-button underline&quot; data-index=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                            Reset
                        &lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;!-- Slant Controls --&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;slider-container&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;div class=&quot;slider-controls&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;label for=&quot;text-slant&quot; class=&quot;slider-label&quot;&gt;
                            Slant: &lt;span class=&quot;output&quot; data-index=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  
                        &lt;/label&gt;
                        &lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;800&quot; value=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;slider&quot; id=&quot;text-slant&quot; name=&quot;text-slant&quot; data-index=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
                        &lt;a class=&quot;slider-button underline&quot; data-index=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                            Reset
                        &lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                   &lt;!-- Angle Control --&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;slider-container&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;slider-controls&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;label for=&quot;text-angle&quot; class=&quot;slider-label&quot;&gt;
                            Angle: &lt;span class=&quot;output&quot; data-index=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  
                        &lt;/label&gt;
                        &lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;800&quot; value=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;slider&quot; id=&quot;text-angle&quot; name=&quot;text-angle&quot; data-index=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
                        &lt;a class=&quot;slider-button underline&quot; data-index=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                            Reset
                        &lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
    
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/main&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


      &lt;!-- SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST 
        SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST
        SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST SLIDER TEST --&gt;


    &lt;h4&gt;Interchanging the base component&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        We’ve seen now how smaller adjustments of the base component change the appearance of letters. But we can even go beyond smaller adjustments in the form and interchange the base component more radically. Choose a form below to see how it alters the letterforms and what interesting coincidences appear through that.
    &lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;component-change&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;variant-a&quot; class=&quot;component-changer active-changer&quot;&gt;
                &lt;span&gt; ° &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;variant-b&quot; class=&quot;component-changer inactive-changer&quot;&gt;
                &lt;span&gt; ° &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;variant-c&quot; class=&quot;component-changer inactive-changer&quot;&gt;
                &lt;span&gt; ° &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;variant-d&quot; class=&quot;component-changer inactive-changer&quot;&gt;
                &lt;span&gt; ° &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;text-stage&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span id=&quot;stagetext&quot; class=&quot;stage-text screenmemories-base&quot; role=&quot;textbox&quot; contenteditable=&quot;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;All in all, it’s very interesting to see how much is possible within a restricted grid and frame and to how many interesting results an exploration like this can lead. Below, you can find more screenshots of the design process and component alternatives as well as coincidences that happened along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;
                
        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-cont&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;preview-dummy&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img class=&quot;lettering-gallery-preview preview-transform&quot; src=&quot;assets/img/posts/screen-memories/screen-memories-gallery-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;lettering-gallery-img&quot; /&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

    &lt;p&gt; 
        I hope you enjoyed this exploration. I designed this font as a part of the type design course &quot;Screen Memories&quot; under the guidance of Prof. Pierre-Pane-Farré, summer semester 2022, HAW Hamburg. 
        &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        Thanks for reading! 😊 
    &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;script&gt;    
    document.getElementById(&quot;variant-a&quot;).addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, fontVariantA);
    function fontVariantA() {
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.add(&quot;font-variant-a&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-b&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-c&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-d&quot;);

        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-a&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-b&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-c&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-d&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        
    }


    document.getElementById(&quot;variant-b&quot;).addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, fontVariantB);
    function fontVariantB() {
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.add(&quot;font-variant-b&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-a&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-c&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-d&quot;);

        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-b&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-a&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-c&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-d&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
    }

    document.getElementById(&quot;variant-c&quot;).addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, fontVariantC);
    function fontVariantC() {
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.add(&quot;font-variant-c&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-a&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-b&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-d&quot;);

        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-c&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-a&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-b&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-d&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
    }

    document.getElementById(&quot;variant-d&quot;).addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, fontVariantD);
    function fontVariantD() {
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.add(&quot;font-variant-d&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-a&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-b&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;stagetext&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;font-variant-c&quot;);

        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-d&quot;).classList.remove(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-a&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-b&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
        document.getElementById(&quot;variant-c&quot;).classList.add(&quot;inactive-changer&quot;);
    }


// VARIABLE SLIDER TESTS
// ================================================================================================

const container = document.querySelector(&quot;.interactive-slider-container&quot;);
const sliders = document.querySelectorAll(&quot;.slider&quot;);
const sliderValues = document.querySelectorAll(&quot;.output&quot;);
const buttons = document.querySelectorAll(&quot;.slider-button&quot;);

// Display property values
for (let i = 0; i &lt; sliders.length; i++) {
  sliderValues[i].innerHTML = sliders[i].value;
}

// Update text property and displayed property value for each slider
sliders.forEach(slider =&gt; {
    const sliderIndex = slider.getAttribute(&quot;data-index&quot;);
    const output = document.querySelector(`.output[data-index=&quot;${sliderIndex}&quot;]`);
    slider.oninput = function() {
      container.style.setProperty(`--${this.id}`, this.value);
      output.innerHTML = this.value;
    };
  });

// Reset text property and update display property value for each slider
buttons.forEach(button =&gt; {
  const buttonIndex = button.getAttribute(&quot;data-index&quot;);
  const resetOutput = document.querySelector(
    `.output[data-index=&quot;${buttonIndex}&quot;]`
  );
  const resetSlider = document.querySelector(
    `.slider[data-index=&quot;${buttonIndex}&quot;]`
  );
  button.onclick = function() {
    container.style.removeProperty(`--${resetSlider.id}`);
    resetOutput.innerHTML = resetSlider.defaultValue;
    resetSlider.value = resetSlider.defaultValue;
    console.log(resetSlider.defaultValue);
  };
});



&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Typedesign" /><summary type="html">A component-based variable font experiment At the base of most design systems, there is a grid. A grid can help to organize a design, structure it’s contents and give guidance by establishing a visual hirarchy – but it can also be a restriction. Especially in the early days of digitalization, low screen resolutions created clear technical boundaries on how graphics could be displayed. At the very latest with the distribution of the first personal computers using visual interfaces, a formerly niche area in design became more and more important: digital interface design. Due to rather low resolutions in early displays, designers then had to deal with the challenge of transferring formerly unrestricted design rules and patterns into very tight corset of units, the pixels, in the best way possible. This led to a whole new aesthetic of shapes, especially for fonts – curves and other letterform details needed to be pressed in a tight, rectangular pixel grid. Thanks to the technical development of display resolutions in the last decades, designers now have more possibilities than ever to produce fine-detailed forms and display them in every way possible. But the aesthetics of pixelated fonts are still in our minds today and remind us of the early days of digital applications. Lowercase letter N in high resolution with fine details (left) and approximations using different grids (font: Open Sans) Designing graphics under tight restrictions like these is also interesting in the way that it forces us to reduce forms to their necessary essence, so that we can still recognise them. So in a way, early digital fonts were also unavoidably minimalistic. Another development in the technology of digital fonts in the last years is the concept of variable fonts. Variable means that forms can be gradually transformed from one variant to another –  and every possible step in between can be displayed as well. With this feature, variable fonts open up a great range of possibilities in design. Principle of variable fonts: the complete range between two designed states of a form (A and B) can be computed The idea: combining the old and the new While studying the possibilities of variable fonts and the history of early digital fonts, the idea of combining aspects of both of them formed: the flexibility of variable fonts in interplay with the restrictions of early pixel fonts. This article illustrates the outcome of my experiments about creating a digital font that combines a restricted grid together with flexible, variable units (components). Before going into the experiments, let me shortly introduce the thoughts behind the construction of the letters. The letters are constructed in a grid of rows. The basic style is a regular sans serif. A special feature of the font is the extreme high x-height, the low space for ascenders and the completely missing space for descenders (meaning the descenders are fit inside of the x-height space. This underlines the restriction of fitting letters in a very small space and at the same times allows for the font to be used with a very narrow line height. Weight variations of the letter A. You can see how the components align to the grid The extreme x-height and the absence of ascenders allows the font to be set with very low line-heights Introducing variable components There are four axes in this variable font that can each be manipulated seperately. Every axis affects the base component of the letters differently, as demonstrated below: ° Weight ° Form ° Slant ° Angle The four variable axes in the base component: Thickness, Form, Slant and Angle The adjustment of the basic component in different axes allows for the letters to change its properties and appearance completely. We can not only change one axis and one property at a time, but iterate between different axes and let the application calculate all possible versions in between, which leads to some interesting results. Letterform construction The letterforms themselves are entirely constructed of the base components shown above. A change in the base components leads to a change of the whole letter. Aditionally to the change in the base component itself, the arrangement that makes up the letter can be adjusted, in this case for creating an italic version with the Slant Axis. Hover over the letters to see how each axis affects the look of the letter. Weight ^ A&amp;nbsp; Form ^ A&amp;nbsp; Slant ^ A&amp;nbsp; Component Angle ^ A&amp;nbsp; Character Set The font includes all uppercase and lowercase letters, the numbers and basic interpunctuation. Upper- and lowercase alphabet Numbers and basic punctuation Manipulating the axes The basic principle is clear – a manipulation of the base component changes the apperance of the letter. Now, we can change the properties of the font and mix between the axes to our liking. Use the editor below to adjust the axes of the font. You can also enter your own text! Hello Weight: Reset Form: Reset Slant: Reset Angle: Reset Interchanging the base component We’ve seen now how smaller adjustments of the base component change the appearance of letters. But we can even go beyond smaller adjustments in the form and interchange the base component more radically. Choose a form below to see how it alters the letterforms and what interesting coincidences appear through that. ° ° ° ° &amp;nbsp;Hello&amp;nbsp; All in all, it’s very interesting to see how much is possible within a restricted grid and frame and to how many interesting results an exploration like this can lead. Below, you can find more screenshots of the design process and component alternatives as well as coincidences that happened along the way. I hope you enjoyed this exploration. I designed this font as a part of the type design course &quot;Screen Memories&quot; under the guidance of Prof. Pierre-Pane-Farré, summer semester 2022, HAW Hamburg. Thanks for reading! 😊</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WC for Humans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WC for Humans" /><published>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wc-for-humans">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;Time to be more equal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equality starts somewhere in our day to day life – and sometimes, it can be small things that make life a tiny bit easier and better for everyone. Finding a restroom in a public place is often more complicated than necessary. Everyone knows how annoying long waiting times at social events are, and often, the surroundings are very beneficial to mens needs. And as if that alone would’t be enough trouble already, the common men / women approach to labeling restrooms can leave non-binary people feel unseen and mistreated. So maybe, instead of labeling too much, a good approach could be to focus on what truly unites us all –  we are human beings with dignity and deserve to have equal possibilities. Even if it’s just the fact that we could all go to the toilet in peace. I think making public toilets accessible for everyone might be a small step into the right direction.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With that being said, I was very happy to create this sign-concept for the café &lt;i&gt;Dreamy Donuts&lt;/i&gt; in Hamburg. The goal was to find a matching approach to the look of the interiors, stand out visually, and just be joyful to see – a perfect call for a unique, handmade sign. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first things to sort out were possible materials and techniques that would help to transport the desired look and feel and to match the interiors of the café. The surroundings create a welcoming atmosphere with stable, wooden furniture and warm lighting, plants let the rooms come alive, and everything is flooded with daylight. The signs should blend into that atmosphere and be lively and characteristic on their own. So instead of having common plastic letters, the sign should have nice haptics and stand out – literally. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My approach to achieve that look was to use wood as the basic material. This idea came up naturally, as it fits the wooden interior just right. And fortunately, there’s a good way to produce very precise cutouts from wood – by using a lasercutter!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But before cutting, the visual concepts needs to be worked out. So after researching for a while and gathering ideas, I started with first sketches to define possible letterforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;First style exploration with playful, ornamental letterforms&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first exploration led to a playful, kind of ornamental shape form of letters. While the shapes fit well together and build a harmonic unit, they seemed a bit too complex. The small details would possibly have caused trouble in the production and the thin strokes would be very fragile. Also, the style of letters might have been too classic, an attribute that would not have fit the modern character of the café so well.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So for the next approach, I chose to go for bolder, clearer shapes. Also, the interconnections of letters should be stronger and more resistant in case the signs would be touched or moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Second approach with bolder, clearer letterforms&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolder letterforms, stronger interconnections and less tiny details led to a clearer, more modern look. The overall style fit the desired character way better and seemed to be functioning just right. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the word &lt;i&gt;Humans&lt;/i&gt; on it’s own would not be too obvious and still leave much room for interpretation, there needed to be another clear indicator to clarify that these are restrooms. To create a contrast to the wooden sign and to let it be the main eye catcher, I decided to go for a flat, minimalist approach in form of a sticker. While another part made of wooden letters would have been too small-detailed to cut precisely and would compete with the main word &lt;i&gt;Humans&lt;/i&gt;, the sticker would not steal the attention and complement the wooden letters instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Adding complementary indicator for the restrooms&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the basic concept for the sign is fitting and works fine, it’s time to work out the details and vectorize the artwork. For the production of the sign, a clean and precise layout is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-04.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Vectorizing the lettering and making adjustments in the process &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the vectorization process, the design is tweaked until it fits just right. In this example, you can see how the spacing and the details of the individual letterforms are adjusted. Also, the size and spacing for the matching sticker need to be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Final lettering and sticker design ready for production&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the design is finished, it’s time for production. The letters are cut out of solid wooden board with the help of a lasercutter (for this, I worked together with &lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lasercut.hamburg/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lasercut.hamburg&lt;/a&gt;) and the stickers are plotted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Lasercut wooden letters with tape on the back side&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cut wooden letters have a nice texture that make the sign even more haptic and interesting to look at. On the back side, you see the tape to stick the letters to the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Positioning the sign on the door by using a stencil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to place the sign! Using the stencil, the position can be adjusted until it’s just right. When the position is found, the only thing that’s left is to glue it to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/wc-for-humans/humans-article-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;The finished sign hanging on the door&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Et voilà – everything is finished and installed. Now we have a beautiful, unique sign to welcome everyone to the restrooms. When there’s so much love to the detail even for the toilet signs, imagine how good the food will taste! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking" /><summary type="html">Time to be more equal</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extra Butter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extra Butter" /><published>2019-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/extra-butter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/extra-butter">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;A bit of extra butter on top&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea to Extra Butter came up in the process of a fun screen printing workshop, when the 
&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://timfeuring.de/swipe-studio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Swipe Studio Logo&lt;/a&gt;
 was printed on all kind of fabrics. For a similar event, the plan was to create another visually appealing and bold lettering – which finally led to the creation of the Extra Butter logo mark.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From initial lettering as a pencil-sketch to refined vector artwork, it evolved to its final, playful look. It was later on used for screen-printing and now embellishes diverse clothes and fabrics from shirts to shopping bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;First rough sketches to determine the basic arrangement of letters&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first – sketching out ideas!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To get ideas on paper and find first directions to explore further, I always start with small scale sketches. Sketching by hand allows to quickly test out possible arrangements, to take notes and iterate. Nothing has to be perfect in this stage, it’s just about exploring, getting to know the letters and find possible combinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Drawing the letters with brush pens (left) and round nibs (right) to explore letterforms and to test out possible details&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When feeling confident with my ideas and after having chosen a vague direction, I like to explore further on paper with different kinds of pens. Different tools have their own look and feel, and the emerging characteristics from this step can help to narrow down details like stroke widths, contrasts and spacing - even at an early stage with rough sketches. In this case, a contrast in stroke width seemed to be a promising approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;First digital sketches to figure out contrasts in the letters and to refine the arrangement &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to refine the sketches, determine shapes, to figure out how letters  intertwine into each other. In this case, I chose to work digitally with a graphic tablet. The arrangement of letters gets tighter, details get clearer and clearer, and the forms start to grow together to form a unit. A grid in the Background helps with spacing. This is one of the most crucial steps to get the design just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-04.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Stages of the vectorization show the adjustments made in certain areas&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the sketches are ready, the letterforms are rebuilt as vectors. In this stage, the arrangement and letterforms are set, but smaller adjustments can still be made in the process. Notice how the bowel of the B was changed to be more open and the horizontal lines of the T were made thinner to match the contrast of the other letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt; The refined lettering in vector view &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo mark is now vectorized in its final form and basically ready to print. To make it even more interesting, I added a 3D-effect to it to give the illusion of dimension. Now, the logo mark can be used for all kinds of purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/extra-butter/extra-butter-article-06.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Animated GIF of the lettering&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the use in digital applications, the graphic could also be animated to create an interesting effect and add attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">A bit of extra butter on top</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dreamy Donuts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dreamy Donuts" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreamy-donuts">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;It’s a sign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet donuts, delicious cakes, perfect coffee with latte-art on it and everything else you could wish for in a café. You just feel when a restaurant or cafe has that kind of soul to it, when everything is made with love and passion, when people put their hearts in and create beautiful surroundings – to heartily welcome their customers to embrace the sweet things in life. And what underlines handmade, personal, delicious food made with love even more? Exactly, handmade signs made with the same personality and passion. For the grand opening of the cafe, I had the pleasure to design a concept and to hand-paint the signs for the store. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At the beginning of a (signpainting) project, there are always a bunch of open questions. What is the purpose of the sign? Is it a main information source or is it more decorational? Which information exactly should it transport, what are possible ways to produce and what fits best to the customer? What do the commodities allow?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this case, possibilities were pretty much open in any direction. The main goal was to create well-functioning signs that give customers a good orientation and fit to the brand and the style of the location. The overall look and feel should be high-quality, trustworthy, and transport love to the details. Looking for a way to convey these attributes, the idea of hand-painting the signs was close. Handpainted signs have personality. Each sign is unique, each letter individually written for an exact purpose and and exact place. It enrichens the overall look and feel of a location, and beyond plain information, it transports the craftsmnship and love for detail with it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With these questions in mind, the first job to be done before picking up a brush and paint was to sort out information and create a visual concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Starting with the basics: sorting information
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cafe, the menu was rather broad. There were loads of beverages and different kinds of food. In addition, the owner wanted to stay flexible to test out different dishes and see what works out best, especially regarding the donuts and bagels. To solve this problem and narrow it down for the signs, splitting the menu into two categories made sense: one fixed part for the beverages that do not often change, and another part that could be easily adjusted for the food. This way, the beverages would make out the major part of the handpainted signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Sketching out ideas for placement and form of the signs
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clustering the menu and deciding which information should go on the signs, the planning of size and position starts. The location of the café had high ceilings and a broad free space, which allowed for a wide sign of ~5 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Preparing the wooden boards with chalkboard paint
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the chalkboards are all custom tailored. The base is made of wooden board, then chalkboard paint is applied. You can usually get all that is needed for preparing chalk boards from your local hardware store or order the materials online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Measuring and lining down the baselines for the sign. An improvised ruler (left) can help to ease the process
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to prepare for the letters! When transferring the sketches and positions to the board correctly, it is helpful to calculate the amount of rows and columns. Additionally, I like to make myself a kind of ruler with the correct measurements, this saves some time when drawing the baselines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Rough sketches to determine the size of the letters (left) and testing out the sizes on a draft paper before painting on the board (right)
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all the baselines are ready to go and the board is marked. Previously I tested how the size of letters would work out optically. Also, I painted an example row with the final brushes on draft paper to determine the final look and style of letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    The critical phase: painting the menu on the board 
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything set and prepared, lets go! Row by row, I now paint the menu items on the board. At hand is the list to get everything in right order and a wet towel to erase baselines or errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Detail shot of the coffee menu
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding some final details – and it’s finished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    The boards hanging in their final place on the wall
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/dreamy-donuts/dreamy-donuts-article-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;
    Final coffee and tea signs separated
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This signpainting job was particularly fun and challenging. I’m very happy with the end result and I’m looking forward to more similar work.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Signmaking" /><summary type="html">It’s a sign</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Swipe Studio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swipe Studio" /><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/swipe-studio">&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-headline&quot;&gt;A mazing design studio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swipe is SinnerSchraders mobile studio, specialized in creating awesome mobile experiences – and it is the studio I had the luck to absolve my three year graphic design apprenticeship in. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Founded in 2010, it has expanded over time and is now located in the cities of Hamburg, Berlin and Zurich. On a regular basis, we organize activities for team building or just hanging out and having a good time together. In 2019, the suggestion of printing and branding our own clothing by hand came up. The idea for the screen printing workshop was born and with it, the challenge to design appealing graphics that people would want to wear. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Being especially passionate in everything connected to typography and lettering, my wish was to create a bold and interesting logo mark. While gathering inspiration from calligraphers, lettering artists and designers, I found grid-based, geometric type to have especially interesting bold aesthetics with rich contrasts. The idea was set, so let’s start the work! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It all starts with pen and paper. For me personally, sketching is the very best way to get thoughts out of your head, visualize ideas, to test concepts and to see what works and what does not. In my opinion, sketches do not need to be works of art or look especially great. For designing, they are more of a helpful tool for the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;first sketches on paper&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;I.) Letters filling former logo shape &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; II.) Combination of letters and outline of the logo shape&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first approach was to letter Swipe Studio to fit the geometric form of the former Swipe logo, which in the end did not end up working the way I imagined it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;I.) First draft with longer wording &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; II.) Roughly determining the letter shapes &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; III.) Refining positions of the letters &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, sketching the letters in the form of a grid seemed to be a much more promising approach. The interconnection and wrapping of the letters created an interesting aesthetic even in the quick sketches that needed to be explored further. After a few iterations the basic arrangement of the letters started to work out fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt; Process of refining the sketch and turning it into digital&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having set the basis, the next step was to arrange the letters in a geometric grid and to rebuild them as vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Finished logo mark &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the logo only needed some more tweaks to get the contrast and whitespace just right. Fortunately, the constructed form of the letters and the way it was built using stroke vectors allows for quick adjustments of thickness. Et voilà, the logomark is finished!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Below, you can find some impressions from the screen printing workshop and the print results. We printed the logo on tote bags, shirts and even laptop cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Applying the color on the screen (left) and cleaning the screen after the printing process (right) &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;Some of the printed fabrics – laptop cases, shirts and tote bags &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;additional-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/posts/swipe-studio/swipe-article-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;additional-img-desc&quot;&gt;The Swipe Studio logo painted on the studio wall in Hamburg &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the logo mark was designed and intended for having a fun screen printing workshop. But from this point, it started to live its own life. Over time, it was used more and more throughout the studio and eventually became the official Swipe logo that is now being used over several channels and painted over the walls in Hamburg, Berlin and Zurich.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Learn more about Swipe on 
&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/sinnerschrader-swipe-gmbh/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/swipestudio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for reading! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logo creation" /><summary type="html">A mazing design studio</summary></entry></feed>